

Yanbo Xu

Ph.D. Candidate Georgia Institute of Technology

CONTACT ME



asnoppy@gmail.com



218-355-8432



https://yanboxu.github.io



266 Ferst Drive, Atlanta, GA 30313

EDUCATION

2017 - Present PhD Candidate in Machine Learning Georgia Institute of Tech. **GPA 4.0**

2015 - 2016PhD Student in Computer Science Johns Hopkins Univ. **GPA 4.0**

2010 - 2013PhD Student in Language Tech. Carnegie Mellon Univ. **GPA 3.7**

2008 - 2010M.S in Applied Math & Statistics Univ. of Minnesota Duluth

2000 - 2006M.S. & B.S. in Computer Science Harbin Institute of Tech. China

ABOUT ME

My research focus on learning from large scale multi-modal time series data for risk predictions in applications of healthcare. I started my PhD at Carnegie Mellon, working alongside Prof. Jack Mostow on applications of ML in personalized tutoring systems. After taking a brief leave of absence when Jack retired, I resumed my study at Johns Hopkins with Prof. Suchi Saria and moved to Georgia Tech with family. I'm now working with Prof. Jimeng Sun on cutting-edge ML/DL algorithms for healthcare. My research topics include but are not limited to Sequential Modeling, Deep Neural Networks, Bayesian Inference and Causal Analysis.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2020 Summer

Intern at Home Deport (Data Science) Mentored by Walid Shalaby, Xiguan Cui

Subsequent purchase predictions for email recommendations.

2019 Summer

Intern at Microsoft Research AI (Redmond)

Mentored by Emre Kiciman.

Identify candidate users causally for product recommendations.

2014 - 2015

Visiting Scholar at Univ. of California Berkeley

Mentored by Prof. Zach Pardos.

Scale up student models to MOOC platform edX.

2006 - 2008

Software Engineer at Lenovo Group Ltd., China Develop Information Integration System for CCB bank.

AWARDS AND HONORS

2018 Google Summer of Code (GSoC) Developer in R project for statistical computing

2012 Best Student Paper Award at EDM

2010 Outstanding Graduates

Department of Math and Statistics, Univ. of Minnesota Duluth

2010 Data Science Summer Institute Fellowship

University of Illinois Urbana Champaign

2009 NAACL Scholarship Award Johns Hopkins HLT Summer School



Yanbo Xu

Ph.D. Candidate Georgia Institute of Technology

CONTACT ME



asnoppy@gmail.com



218-355-8432



https://yanboxu.github.io



266 Ferst Drive, Atlanta, GA 30313

EDUCATION

2017 – Present PhD Candidate in Machine Learning Georgia Institute of Tech. GPA 4.0

2015 – 2016 PhD Student in Computer Science Johns Hopkins Univ. GPA 4.0

2010 – 2013 PhD Student in Language Tech. Carnegie Mellon Univ. GPA 3.7

2008 – 2010 M.S in Applied Math & Statistics Univ. of Minnesota Duluth

2000 – 2006 M.S. & B.S. in Computer Science Harbin Institute of Tech. China

PREPRINTS

1. Split-Treatments Analysis to Rank Heterogenous Causal Effects for Novel Treatments

Xu, Y., Mahajan, D., Manrao, L., Sharma, A., Kiciman, E. [Submitted]

- 3. Prediction of Step-down Transfer in Post-Operative Norwood Children Using Convolutional Neural Networks on Continuous ECG Waveforms **Xu, Y.,** Hong, S., Sun, J., Aljiffry, A., & Maher, K. [**Submitted**]
- 4. DeepRite: Deep Recurrent Inverse TreatmEnt Weighting for Adjusting Time-varying Confounding in Modern Longitudinal Observational Data **Xu, Y**., Xiao, C., & Sun, J. [arXiv]

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

1. HOLMES: Health OnLine Model Ensemble Serving for Deep Learning Models in Intensive Care Units.

Xu, Y.*, Hong, S.*, Khare, A.*, Priambada, S.&, Maher K., Aljiffry, A*, Sun, J., Tumanov, A. [*Equally contributed]

KDD, 2020

2. RAIM: Recurrent Attentive and Intensive Modeling of Multimodal Continuous Patient Monitoring Data

Xu, Y., Biswal, S., Deshpande, S., Maher, K., & Sun, J.

KDD, 2018

3. Bayesian Estimation of Individualized Treatment-Response Curves in Populations with Heterogeneous Treatment Effects

Xu, Y., Xu, Y., & Saria, S.

JMLR [Accepted with minor revision]

4. Predicting Changes in Pediatric Medical Complexity using Large Longitudinal Health Records

Xu, Y., Bahador, M. T., Searles, E., Thompson, M., Tejedor-Sojo, J., & Sun, J. *AMIA*, 2017

5. A Non-parametric Bayesian Approach for Estimating Treatment-Response Curves from Sparse Time Series

Xu, Y., Xu, Y., & Saria, S.

MLHC. JMLR W&CP, 2016

6. Comparison of methods to trace multiple subskills: Is LR-DBN best? **Xu, Y.**, & Mostow, J.

EDM, 2012 [Best Student Paper Award]